<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chetan Badhe</title>
    <description>Welcome to my website. I'm Chetan Badhe. I'm software developer, and amature writer.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 23:24:30 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 23:24:30 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Journey to the Failed Startup</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-wanted-to-create-history-i-wanted-to-put-a-dent-in-the-universe-to-fulfill-my-desires-id-started-a-startup-and-it-failed-im-going-to-share-my-story&quot;&gt;I wanted to create history. I wanted to put a dent in the universe. To fulfill my desires I’d started a startup and it failed. I’m going to share my story.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being brought up in a typical village in India and having studied in a government school, when I first started using the Internet everything changed. I started gaining knowledge of things that I was never taught at school. Facebook inspiration pages, Steve Jobs Stanford speech etc, made a long-lasting impact on me. Furthermore, it helped me learn about famous entrepreneurs like Bill Gates, Mark Zuckerberg, Richard Branson etc. Reading their life journey created an urge inside me to establish my own startup. I was fascinated by how these people acquired massive wealth without any financial backing. I thought if these people can do it why can’t I? After all, no one wants to work for someone. I wanted to be independent. I wanted to be my own boss. I was 16 then but Bill Gates was only 14 when he started Microsoft. Oh Gosh! I am 2 years late, I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was playing with WordPress and UI then. I was not the hardcore developer who can create an application or website from scratch. My only skill at that time was: I can tweak WordPress theme for my use. So, I’ve decided to start a marketplace for digital goods. I thought (I’m being really serious here) with the growing scope of the Internet and digital devices, digital product marketplace would be a good bet. People will need it. Plus, it was something that I can easily create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started studying about digital products marketplaces which existed earlier. I read the flaws in it and thought I will cover them all and give sleek experience to users. Plus, I’d listed some important features which existing marketplaces lack. I was going to add that features in my marketplace. The vision was ‘Amazon for Digital Goods’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed a team because every great startup needs one. I tried talking to friends and people in my network who would show some interest in my idea and work with me in return for equity. Oh yes, I’d read about how Steve Jobs convinced John Scully to be CEO of Apple. I tried Steve Jobs way of convincing people but nothing worked. These people are missing the opportunity, I thought. I’d decided to go solo and add a co-founder or team when I will find someone who is perfect for the position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I wanted to progress. So, I created marketplace using existing WordPress marketplace theme and tweaked as much as I can. I created a prototype at first. When I would get proper cash flow, I was going to hire web developers. The functioning prototype was ready. Now the next step was bringing sellers to the marketplace. I tried posting on Facebook groups, starting inviting each seller manually two-three sellers agreed but who will place a product on the website with zero customers? Imagine someone wants to sell vegetables in the marketplace of his friend but there is not a single person visiting the place. I didn’t have sellers because of customers and don’t have customers And to the sellers, it was the digital paradox. Meanwhile, I was reading voraciously about the related markets and startups in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I came to the conclusion that I need some money to scale my startup and to start cash flow. I decided to raise the pre-seed round. I’d know how Dropbox raised the pre-seed money from just a YouTube video and here I’d the real product so there was a positive certainty in my mind that I will easily get an investment. The struggle started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read how companies raise investments, how investment works, where to find investments. I created a pitch deck, applied for as many startup accelerators as I could, tried sending pitch deck to investors I know from the Internet. But, nothing worked no one was interested in my idea to revolutionize digital products industry. Well, how could someone invest there hard earned money in a 16-year guy who doesn’t even know how to write an email with proper English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically nothing worked, As the time passed I started losing interest in the idea. As I was learning more and more about the AI, I felt ‘Oh Man! Why are you wasting your precious time on things that already exist’. Finally, after working for nearly one and a half year on the idea itself I decided to shut it down. I did not renew the domain name for my Billion Dollar Startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what really went wrong? The most important thing I missed I think is I was carving for money. I never had interest in that Idea. What I was interested in was creating a startup, having a lavish life, a grand office and being a boss of myself. I was thinking how society will respect me if I made it. I wanted to be next Mark Zuckerberg or Bill Gates. I wanted a lot of money… money… that’s where it all went wrong. I never wanted to do all of these because I really want to solve a real problem. But, I was convincing in my mind that there is the real problem, and I’m solving it. There was no innovation, nothing new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how my pseudo-Billion Dollar Startup failed. But honestly speaking I never felt I’d wasted time. All the experiences were full of learning and taught me things that no one will be able to teach you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://yourstory.com/read/37c7312798-learnings-from-my-fail&quot;&gt;YourStory.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 01:52:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/myself/2018/01/15/journey-to-failed-startup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/myself/2018/01/15/journey-to-failed-startup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Myself</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>बिटकॉइन बद्दल…</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;जर तुम्ही दैनिक घडामोडींच्या सानिद्यात असाल तर ‘बिटकॉइन’ हा शब्द वाचण्यात किंवा ऐकण्यात आलाच असेल. मागील वर्षामध्ये लोक कित्येक लोक बिटकॉइन मध्ये निवेश करून करोडपती झाले. जानेवारी 2017 मध्ये एका बिटकॉइन ची किंमत 50,000 च्या नजदिक होती त्याच बिटकॉइन च्या किमतीने डिसेंबर 2017 मध्ये 13 लाखांची सीमा गाठली. पण बिटकॉइन हि केवळ आणि केवळ एक ‘निवेशीय संधी (Investment Opportunity)’ नसून त्यामागे एक क्रांतिकारक तंत्रज्ञान आहे. ज्याला ब्लॉकचेन (Blockchain) असे संबोधतात. प्रस्तुत लेखा मध्ये बिटकॉइन तंत्रज्ञानाबद्दल विस्तारलेले आहे.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;२००८ मध्ये सतोशी नाकामोटो नावाच्या अनोळखी व्यक्तीने एक रिसर्च पेपर प्रदर्शित केला ज्यामध्ये त्यांनी बिटकॉइन ची संकल्पना मांडली. दैनंदिन जीवनामध्ये पैश्यांच्या च्या देवाणघेवाण साठी बँका आहेत, त्याला नियंत्रित करायला सरकार आहे. आपल्या पारंपरिक व्यवहारामध्ये मध्ये आपण आपले पैसे एका अनोळखी व्यक्ती वा संस्थेकडे म्हणजेच बँकांमध्ये ठेवत असतो. आपल्या सगळ्या व्यवहारांची माहिती बँकेकडे असते. बँकेचे दिवाळे निघणे किंवा जर एखादी बँक बंद पडली तर आपल्या कष्टाने कमावलेले पैसे संपुष्टात येऊ शकता. तसेच, आंतरराष्ट्रीय व्यवहार करण्यासाठी सुद्धा आपल्याला बँकांची मदत घ्यावी लागते. थोडक्यात, आपले सर्व चलनाशी निगडित व्यवहार बँकेवरती अवलंबून असतात.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बिटकॉइन हे डिजिटल चलन आहे. अर्थशास्त्रात व्यवहार करताना एखाद्या व्यक्तीवर अवलंबून असणे याला केंद्रीकरण (Centralisation) असे म्हणतात . यावर उपाय म्हणून सतोशी ने आधुनिक तंत्रज्ञानाचा वापर करून विकेंद्रीकरण (Decentralisation) ची संकल्पना समोर ठेवली. ज्यामध्ये चलनाचे नियंत्रण कुठल्याही एका व्यक्तीकडे किंवा संस्थेकडे नसून फक्त आणि फक्त सामान्य (peer to peer) लोकांकडे राहील. असे चलन कि ज्यावर फक्त आपलेच नियंत्रण राहील. जगामध्ये कुणीही कुठेही घरबसल्या पैसे पाठवू शकेल कुठल्याही मध्यस्ती शिवाय आणि महत्वाचं म्हणजे तुम्ही काय व्यवहार करताय हे फक्त आणि फक्त तुम्हालाच माहिती असेल.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;आता हे थोडं अवाक करण्यासारखं आहे कि एखाद चलन सरकार शिवाय, बँकेशिवाय कार्य कसे करू शकते? आणि जर बिटकॉइन ला सामान्य लोक चालवतात तर मग एखादा व्यक्ती त्याला वाटेल तेवढे बिटकॉइन तयार करून घेऊ शकतो? इत्यादी प्रश्न सामान्यतः पडू शकतात. आधी उल्लेखल्याप्रमाणे बिटकॉइन हे ब्लॉकचेन नावाच्या तंत्रज्ञानावर अवलंबून आहे. ब्लॉकचेन मध्ये जगभरातील बिटकॉइन नेटवर्क वर असणारे लोक जोडलेले असतात. जेंव्हा एखादी व्यक्ती दुसऱ्या व्यक्तीला बिटकॉइन पाठवते तेंव्हा ब्लॉकचेन नेटवर्क त्या व्यवहाराला तपासते. जर व्यवहारासंबंधित सर्व गोष्टी अचूक असतील तर ब्लॉकचेन नेटवर्क व्यवहार सत्यापित करते. यामध्ये अनेक लोक आपापल्या कॉम्प्युटर्स च्या माध्यमातून व्यवहाराला सत्यापित करत असल्यामुळे यामध्ये चुकी होणे अशक्य आहे. तसेच, सतोशी ने स्पष्ट केल्याप्रमाणे एकूण २१ दशलक्ष बिटकॉइन तयार होऊ शकता.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;बिटकॉइन किंवा ब्लॉकचेन जरी समजायला थोडा किचकट विषय असला तरीही हि एका नवीन भविष्याची सुरुवात आहे. अजून खूप बदल व्हायचे आहेत, तंत्रज्ञान हे एका दिवसात जीवन बदलवत नाही, हळू हळू परिणाम दिसायला लागतात. बिटकॉइन कायदेशीर आहे कि नाही यावर भारत सरकारने अजून काहीही स्पष्ट केलेले नाही. तरी ,२०१४ मध्ये भारतीय रिझर्व्ह बँकेचे तत्कालीन गव्हर्नर रघुराम राजन यांनी ‘बिटकॉइन सारख्या डिजिटल करन्सी जास्त लोकप्रियता पावतील’ असे भाष्य केले होते.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 01:52:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/technology,/marathi/2018/01/10/bitcoin-marathi.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/technology,/marathi/2018/01/10/bitcoin-marathi.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Technology,</category>
        
        <category>Marathi</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Era of Chatbots</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We all grew up watching or reading science fiction. Movies have designed specific image of robots, personal assistants. Iron Man’s Jarvis is widely famous for his thinking skills, automating life. Nowadays chatbots are one of the much-talked topic among tech enthusiasts, entrepreneurs, developers, and futurists. Tech giants are betting hard on technologies like machine learning, natural language processing. But, why everyone suddenly got so much interested in chatbots? Why every other tech company, startups are talking about chatbots? What future does it hold?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the days when the world doesn’t have the Internet, using piles of reference books, encyclopedias or dictionaries. People would spend days in libraries if they want to learn something. When the internet was created websites were the hot topics. We could access tons of data in seconds through a website. Websites helped us to organize huge data into a beautiful way. After the smartphone boom when iPhone and Android systems were introduced by respected companies apps were the trending topics. People started preferring apps over using websites because apps were simple, sophisticated and had very fewer chances of spam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Human language is the new user interface”
~ Satya Nadela&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when it comes to chatbots, chatbot’s are simple and user-friendly. You don’t need to install chatbot in your mobile as they are already there when you use messengers apps like Facebook Messenger, Google Allo, Telegram, Kik etc. So forgot the memory issues. You can book a cab, or fix an appointment with a doctor, or schedule your meetings with just a few messages. Chatbots are making everything easier chatbots are new apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The era of conversational agents started when first ELIZA bot created by MIT Artificial Intelligence laboratory passed Turing Test. After it, many experiments kept happening. Apple launched Siri back in 2010, Siri considered as first personal assistant to enter the consumer market. Siri was standalone App on ios created by a startup. Later, Apple acquired that start-up and embedded Siri in its operating system. There was big reason doing so. Bots are the future. When it came to NLP Apple was the first major brand to introduce its personal assistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw the intro to chatbot boom in 2016 when Google introduced its smart messaging application ‘Allo’ following that event Facebook entered in bot’s market with it’s Facebook M. Other messaging services like Kik, Telegram, WeChat, Skype are also offering bot platforms. In first 8 months of 2016 alone chatbot’s had raised over $170M+ in funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;types-of-chatbot-models&quot;&gt;Types of Chatbot Models:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retrieval Based Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In retrieval based models there is set of pre-defined responses. When the query runs chatbots picks a relative response from a set of collection of pre-defined responses. Retrieval Based models can’t generate new sentences. In this type of models, we don’t need to worry about grammar mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early development of chatbot’s started with Retrieval Based models. ELIZA bot, first one to pass widely famous Turing Test was based on the retrieval based model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between 1995 to 2002, Richard Wallace created ALICE bot, known as the advance intellect of ELIZA bot which won Loebner Prize for 3 years. ALICE bot was based on Artificial Intelligence Markup Language (AIML). AIML was XML dialect created for using natural language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative Models:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike retrieval based models, generative models use advanced Machine Learning and NLP algorithms to generate responses. Generative models are quite intelligent. It creates a word to word sentence based on input query which sometimes causes grammatical errors. Generative Models are hard to train but once trained they can outperform retrieval based models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generative type of models considered as future of chatbots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementation of generative based models for NLP is hard when compares with retrieval based models. But services like api.ai or wit.ai makes it pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technological world started taking shape in the form of Artificial Intelligence. Chatbots are apps laced with AI. In future, every small/big business will have chatbot. Isn’t the era of chatbot’s begun?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 01:52:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/technology/2017/07/29/the-era-of-chatbots.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/technology/2017/07/29/the-era-of-chatbots.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Turing Test</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have ever watched the Benedict Cumberbatch starrer “The Imitation Game”, you might be well familiar with who Alan Turing is. Alan Turing was a famous English computer scientist, cryptologist and mathematician who is considered as one of the pioneers of Artificial Intelligence. “Can machines think?” this seemingly inane and rather strange question bothered him. He researched further. While working on these thinking machines, he found a need to test machine’s intelligence so he created a test in 1950 which is eponymously named after him and has quite become synonymous with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turing suggested that by the year 2000, the average interrogator would have less than a 70% chance of making the right decision after five minutes of questioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does the Turing test take place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turing test involves 3 people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An Interrogator (Human, Male or Female)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Human (Either male or Female)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Computer/Machine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three of this people sit in position as shown in below figure. Precaution should be taken that the interrogator cannot see the other two participants i.e. the human and the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the test begins, the interrogator will ask questions to the participants and he has to decide whether the answerer is human or machine. To keep it strict and information leak proof and not let the interrogator decide by voice, the questions and answers should be in written format, preferably in typewritten format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Interrogator fails to differentiate between them, then it is considered that the machine has passed the Turing Test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eugene Goostman, a chatterbot created by three Russian programmers has &lt;a href=&quot;https://gizmodo.com/this-is-the-first-computer-in-history-to-have-passed-th-1587780232?utm_campaign=socialflow_gizmodo_facebook&amp;amp;utm_source=gizmodo_facebook&amp;amp;utm_medium=socialflow&quot;&gt;passed the Turing test for first time&lt;/a&gt;. On 7 June 2014, in a Turing test competition at the Royal Society, organized by Kevin Warwick of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Reading&quot;&gt;University of Reading&lt;/a&gt; to mark the 60th anniversary of Turing’s death, Goostman won after 33% of the judges were convinced that the bot is human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1990, New York businessman Hugh Loebner set up the annual Loebner Prize competition with a prize of $100,000 to the creator of a machine that could pass the Turing Test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of &lt;a href=&quot;loebner.net/Prizef/loebner-prize.html&quot;&gt;Loebner Prize winners&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you might ask why the Turing test is important. It is true that the importance of the Turing test has been widely debated since its inception and it does have some weaknesses with the most prominent being that some human behavior is unintelligent and some intelligent behavior is inhuman. Also, the test is concerned with how the machine acts not necessarily if it has a mind. As John Searle, eminent philosopher argues that action or external behavior cannot necessarily prove that the subject has a mind, which is a legitimate point. Even Alan Turing himself anticipated that criticism or argument. These design flaws puts the test in a position where it is of little relevance in pragmatic fields for today’s scientists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But being one of the first and crucial steps in asking whether a machine can ‘think’ or giving it some anthropomorphic qualities along with its simplicity makes the Turing test important and one of the founding steps for the birth of Artificial Intelligence. Nevertheless, ‘I, Robot’ anyone (the book of course)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally published at &lt;a href=&quot;http://feynmand.com&quot;&gt;feynmand.com&lt;/a&gt; on May 13, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 01:52:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/technology/2017/05/13/the-turing-test.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/technology/2017/05/13/the-turing-test.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
